Frederick Hammersley
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Frederick Hammersley papers
1897-2008, bulk 1940-2000
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Hammersley, Frederick
10.3 linear feet
The papers of Los Angeles Abstract Classicist painter and teacher Frederick Hammersley measure 10.3 linear feet and date from 1897 to 2008, with the bulk of the material dating from 1940 to 2000. The papers contain biographical materials, diaries, family and professional correspondence, personal business and financial records, writings, photographs, printed materials, and works of art.
Provenance
Frederick Hammersley donated his papers to the Archives of American Art in nine accessions from 1974 to 2008.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Frederick Hammersley (1919-2009) spent most of his career in the Los Angeles area working as a painter and teacher. He is closely associated with the hard-edge abstraction painting style of the Abstract Classicists of southern California
Hammersley was born on January 5, 1919 in Salt Lake City, where his father worked for the U.S. Department of the Interior. The family lived in Utah and Idaho before finally settling in San Francisco. Hammersley attended the University of Idaho and later enrolled in the Academy of Advertising Art in San Francisco. In 1940, Hammersley began taking classes at the Chouinard Art Institution in Los Angeles.
Hammersley's studies were interrupted by World War II military service from 1942 to 1946. He was stationed first in Paris as a draftsman in the Signal Corp and was eventually promoted to Army sargeant in the Office of Military Government in Berlin. While in Paris, he visited Picasso's studio several times and also took classes at the école des Beaux Arts at the end of the war. When he returned home in 1946, the GI Bill subsidized his final year of study at Chouinard, now the California Institute of Arts, and three years at Jepson Art Institute in Los Angeles.
Hammersley made his living as an art professor in California for twenty years, teaching at Jepson and Pomona College in Claremont. He accepted a teaching position at the University of New Mexico in 1968 and moved to Albuquerque. In 1971, Hammersley resigned his teaching position and devoted himself to painting.
Hammersley's reputaton as a painter began in 1948 when one of his small paintings was accepted in an annual exhibition at the San Francisco Museum of Modern Art. In 1958, several of his works were included in a traveling exhibition called Four Abstract Classicists, organized by the Los Angeles County Museum of Art. Hammersley, and fellow painters Lorser Feitelson, Karl Benjamin, and John McLaughlin, were dubbed the "hard-edged painters," which consisted of flat, colored geometric shapes that were a sharp contrast to the more popular Abstract Expressionism. The label stuck and in the mid 1970s, Hammersley submitted several works of art for a show called L.A. Hard Edge - the 50s and 70s in Los Angeles.
During the late 1970s and 80s, Hammersley had several exhibitions, including shows at L. A. Louver in Venice, California, Hoshour Gallery in Albuquerque, and the Corcoran in Washington, DC. In 2000, the Laguna Art Museum presented a traveling exhibition organized by the Museum of Fine Arts in Sante Fe and the Pomona College Museum of Art organized a retrospective in 2007. His work is in museum collections across the country, including the Los Angeles County Museum of Art (LACMA), the San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, the Santa Barbara Museum of Art, the Albright-Knox Art Gallery in Buffalo, and the Corcoran Gallery of Art. Hammersley died in 2009 at the age of 90.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Los Angeles Abstract Classicist painter and art teacher Frederick Hammersley measure 10.3 linear feet and date from 1897 to 2008, with the bulk of the material dating from 1940 to 2000. The papers contain biographical materials, diaries, family and professional correspondence, personal business and financial records, writings, photographs, printed materials, and works of art.
Biographical materials includes resumes and biographies, calendars, military records, family genealogies and estate settlement files, school records, high school and college yearbooks, wills and other legal records, and awards. There is one undated and untranscribed audio cassette recording of an interview with Hammersley.
Diaries are found for Hammersley's high school and college years and include notes about classes, friends, and family. There are also scattered entries from his years in Paris during the World War II. There is a large gap in the diaries from 1952 to 1969, and more regular entries dating from 1970-1973, 1979, and 1989. A more complete diary dates from 1991-1995.
Measuring almost three inear feet, correspondence is the largest and most extensive series and consists of letters from family and close friends as well as business correspondence with collectors and professional art associations. Family correspondents include Hammersley's immediate family and aunts and cousins. There is a large amount of correspondence with his sister, Susie Hammersley Stone, that begins in 1949 and contains Hammersley's more personal observations about his art. Additional noteworthy correspondents include fellow artists Rico Lebrun, John McLaughlin, Karl Benjamin, Robert Chuey, and William Brice.
General financial and business records focus on Hammersley business relationships and transactions with galleries and museums and his efforts to promote his art. Galleries and museums represented in the files include Modernism Gallery (San Francisco), L. A. Louver Gallery (Venice, California), and Hoshour Gallery (Albuquerque). This series also contains tax returns and expense ledgers.
Hammersley's writings include college class notes, essays, poetry, lecture and teaching notes, grant applications, and proposals. There are also drafts and a final copy of an article published in the journal Leonardo in 1970. The lecture and teaching notes are supplemented by five audio cassette recordings from Hammersley's lectures at the Albuquerque Museum, Hoshour Gallery, and Graham Gallery.
Photographs include snapshots of Hammersley; images of Hammersely with family and friends; travel photographs, many of them taken in Europe during World War II; photographs of exhibitions; and photographs of Hammersley's artwork. Most of the photographs were labeled and dated by Hammersley.
Printed material consists of newspaper and magazine clippings, exhibition catalogs and announcements, and printed copies of Hammersley graphic designs. The series is quite complete, containing clippings and exhibition material that represents Hammersley's entire career as an artist. The design prints depict the work of the graphic design business that Hammersley operated for over twenty years.
Artwork includes the original designs from Hammersley's graphic design projects, sketchbooks, drawings and designs from high school and college classes, exhibiton catalog drawings, and cards and printouts from his computer drawing series.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 7 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1897, 1927-2003 (Box 1-2, 10; 1.6 linear feet)
Series 2: Diaries, 1935-1951, 1970-1979, 1985, 1991-1995 (Box 2; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 3: Correspondence, circa 1938-2004 (Box 2-4, 14; 2.6 linear feet)
Series 4: General Financial and Business Records, 1936-2005 (Box 5-6; 2 linear feet)
Series 5: Writings, 1940-1996 (Box 7; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 6: Photographs, circa 1922-2007 (Box 7-8; 1 linear foot)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1935-2008 (Box 8-9, 11; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 8: Artwork, 1940-1973 (Box 9; 0.9 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
Painting, Abstract; Painters--California--Los Angeles; Painters--New Mexico--Albuquerque; Computer Art; Art teacher--California--Los Angeles; World War, 1939-1945--France
Types of Materials:
Awards; Designs; Diaries; Drafts (documents); Drawings; Essays; Financial records; Genealogies; Interviews; Lecture notes; Lectures; Poetry; Photographs--aat; Resumes; Sketchbooks; Sound recordings
Names:
Benjamin, Karl; Brice, William, 1921-; Chuey, Robert; Lebrun, Rico, 1900-1964; MvLaughlin, John, 1898-1976; Stone, Susie Hammersley; Hoshour Gallery; L.A. Louver Gallery; Modernism (Gallery)
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1897, 1927-2003, Series 1:; (Box 1-2, 10; 1.6 linear ft.)
  This series contains resumes, biographies, calendars, military records, postcards from travels, awards and certificates, school records, and yearbooks. Wills and estate records are found for Hammersley and several of his relatives, including parents, grandfather, and a great aunt. The original 1897 mortgage deed from property his grandfather owned in London is found here. Of particular interest are the German souvenirs that Hammersley brought back from his time in the army during World War II.
  - Awards and Certificates, 1927-1930, 1934, (oversized items housed in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Awards, circa 1970, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographies and Resumes, circa 1959-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - British Cigarette Boxes, circa 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Calendars, 1955-1975, 1982-1999, (4 folders, oversized items housed in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
  - Census, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Class Attendance and Report Cards, 1935-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Diploma - High School, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Estate - Anna Hammersley (Hammersley's mother), 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Estate - Dorothy Hutchinson Hammersley (Hammersley's aunt), 1969, 1974-1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Estate - Frederick Hammersley (Hammersley's grandfather), 1966-1987, (oversized item housed in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Maude Eliza Hammersley Estate, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Family Genealogy, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Gallery Catalogs, Post Cards, and Tour Guides - England, circa 1944-1947 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - German Souvenirs, 1944, (oversized items in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Harold Hammersley's Art (Hammersley's father), 1960, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Interview with Hammersley - Audio Cassette Tape (not transcribed), Undated, (Item housed in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Life Insurance Policy, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Location of Hammersley's Important Papers, 1967, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Military Records and Documents, 1933-1946 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Montana Property, circa 1977-2001 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Post Cards and Travel Guides, circa 1940-1949, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
  - Program from the Chief Theatre Opening - Pocatello, Idaho, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Susie Hammersley Stone (Hammersley's sister), 1947-1951, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Theater and Art Gallery Programs - Paris, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - U.S. Navy Combat Art Collection, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Who's Who in American Art Entries, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Will and Estate Documents, 1992-1996, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Yearbook - Salt Lake City High School, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Yearbook - Salt Lake City High School, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Yearbooks - University of Idaho, 1937-1938, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Oversized Awards and Certificates, 1930, 1934, (from Box 1, F. 1) (Box 10)
  - Oversized Calendars, 1967-1968, 1970, 1974-1975, (2 folders, from Box 1, F. 5-8) (Box 10)
  - Oversized German Souvenirs - Rubber Stamps, circa 1944, (from Box 1, F. 18) (Box 10)
  - Interview with Hammersley - Audio Cassette Tape (not transcribed), Undated, (from Box 1, F. 20) (Box 11)
  - Oversized Mortgage Deed, Frederick Hammersley (Hammerley's Grandfather), 1897, (from Box 1, F. 14) (Box 10)
  - Oversized Scrapbook of Career Highlights, 1944-1969, (from Box 2, F. 9) (Box 10)
- Diaries, 1935-1951, 1970-1979, 1985, 1991-1995, Series 2:; (Box 2, 0.2 linear ft.)
  Early diaries dating from 1931 provide information about Hammersley's life during high school and college, including details about classes, social activities, weather, and his relationship with his parents and sister. Although sporadic after 1947, the 1945 diary records observations about his year in Paris as an army sargeant and reveals his renewed interest in art. The diary covering the years from 1991 to 1995 documents his daily routine and provides interesting details about his painting and exhibition schedules.
  Diaries are arranged chronologically by date.
  - Diaries, 1935-1951, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
  - Diaries, 1970-1973, 1979, 1985, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Diaries, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, circa 1938-2004, Series 3:; (Box 2-4, 14; 2.6 linear feet)
  This series includes personal and professional correspondence from his first year in college through the end of his life. There is correspondence with galleries, museums, professional associations, colleagues, family, and friends. Letters from his sister, Susie Hammersley Stone, are particularly complete and detailed. Also included in this series are letters that document Hammersley's mentoring of several students in his classes at Pomona College. Photographs, clippings, and other miscellaneious enclosures are also be found in some of the letters.
  Correspondents include Karl Benjamin, William Brice, Robert Chuey, Wayne Entice, Claudine Humblet, Stanley Kiesel, Rico Lebrun, and John McLaughlin. Galleries and museums representd in Hammersley's correspondence include the Corcoran Gallery of Art, Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, Heritage Gallery, Laguna Art Museum, New Mexico Museum of Art, San Francisco Museum of Art, and Santa Fe East Gallery
  The series is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. Miscellaneous folders for the alphabet contain single letters from individuals. Drafts of outgoing letters are arranged chronologically at the end of the series.
  - A Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ace Gallery, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Clinton and Mary Adams, 1981-1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Albuquerque Museum, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bardene Allen, 1959-2000, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Gwynne and Evelyn Allen, 1959-1998 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Jeanne and Garo Antreasian, 1975-1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Donna Ari, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1980, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Artspace - Southwestern Contemporary Arts Quarterly, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Awards in the Visual Arts, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - B Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - John and Dorothy Barbour, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Joe Barrett, 1994-1999 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Karl Benjamin, 1962-2004, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
  - Barry and Gail Berkus, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - William Brice, 1989-1999 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Nicholas Brigante, 1979-1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Gerald Brommer, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Gerald Buck, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Kathleen and Charles Brown, 1966, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - C Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - California State University - Fine Arts Gallery, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Myriane Chariez, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Chouinard Art School, 1964-1968, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - The Chouinard Foundation, 1999-2007 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Bob and Josephine Chuey, circa 1973-1992 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Kenneth Clark, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Frederick and Ellen Landis Cohn, circa 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Van Coke, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Contemporary Art Society of New Mexico, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1966-1991 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Marcus Crandall, 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Daisy Cross, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - D Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Eldon and Virginia Dedini, 1986-2002 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Bette Dunavant, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - E Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Susan Ehrlich, 1981-2003 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Bob and Barbara Ellis, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Wayne Entice, 1970-2002 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sam and Elena Erenberg, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Merion Estes, circa 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - F Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lorser and Helen Feitelson, 1978, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fellows of Contemporary Art, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fine Arts Gallery, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bernice Fletcher, 1968-1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bill and Judy Fletcher, circa 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Craig Fletcher, 1997-2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pat Fogle, 1963-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Piper Fogle (Yost), 1965-1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Madelyn Foreman, 1971-1972, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Anne and Bill Frej, 1991-2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Noriko Fuginami, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Charles O. Furniss, 1961-1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - G Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - William George, 1992-2002 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Norman Geske (National Bank of Commerce, Nebraska), 1973-1981, (Oversized item housed in OV 14) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Getty Research Institute, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Jim and Nancy Grant, 1950-1960 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Graphis, 1952-1953, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Guggenheim Museum, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - H Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Anna Hammersley (Hammersley's Mother), 1956-1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Harold Hammersley (Hammersley's Father), circa 1938-1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Harold and Anna Hammersley (Hammersley's Parents),1942-1944, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Victor Hammersley (Hammersley's Uncle), 1962-1966 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Mary Harris, circa 1970, 1984-2000 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Yoshimi Hayashi, 2000-2004 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Heritage Gallery, 1960-1988 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Heydt/Bair Gallery, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Flora Hill, circa 1982-1999 (Box 3, Folder 33-34)
  - Mildred Hodges, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Michel and Madge Hogan, 1954-1973 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Roger Hollenbeck, 1959-1973 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Jim Hueter, 1974-2003, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
  - Claudine Humblet, 1985-2001, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 40-42)
  - I Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - J Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Herb and Marcia Jepson, circa 1950-1993 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Betsy Jones, circa 1954-2003, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 46-47)
  - K Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Sakae Kawashiri, 1944, 1980-1999 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Peter and Brenda Kelly, 1985-1997 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Albert and Joan Kessler, 1984-1991 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Stanley Kiesel, 1968-1989 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Ann King, 1971, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Robert King, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Gloria Koehl, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Ray Kuhne, 1981-1994 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - L Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Laguna Art Museum, 1993-2000 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Susan Larrabee, 1976-2000 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Tom and Patti Laursen, 1962-1992, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 60-61)
  - Charles and Jinny Lawler, 1959-1993 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Rico and Constance Lebrun, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Leonardo - International Journal of the Contemporary Artist, 1969-1970, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Linda Durham Gallery, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Charles Littler, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Ernest Lopez, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Los Angles County Museum of Art, 1966, 1976-1991 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Los Angeles Times, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Bates Lowry, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Peter Ludwig, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - M Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - McCrory Corporation, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Gardner McFall (Middendorf/Lane), circa 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - John McLaughlin, circa 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Museum of Albuquerque, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1961-1997 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Museum of New Mexico, 1973-1999 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Donald Muth, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - N Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - National Museum of American Art, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - New Mexico Arts and Crafts Fair, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - New Mexico Farm and Ranch Heritage Museum, 1997-2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - New Mexico State Fair, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Nora Eccles Harrison Museum of Art - Utah State University, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Betty Nowels, 1974-2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Paula Nowels, 1977-2004 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - O Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - P Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Pacific Arts Association, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Pomona College, 1953-1980, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bob Perine, 1981-1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Victor Quan, 1954, 1979-1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - R Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - R. C. Erpf Gallery, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Recommendation Letters, 1959-1983, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Roswell Museum and Art Center, 1979, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Richard Rowlands, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Wesley Rusnell, 1979-2003 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Ruth Bachofner, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - S Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1965-1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - San Francisco State College, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Santa Fe East Galleries, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Santa Fe Festival of the Arts, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Kurt Schettling, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Herman Schneiderman, circa 1968-1989 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Peter Selz, 1959-1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Stuart Shedletsky - "Still Working" Exhibition, 1991-1996 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Milt Shields, circa 1962 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Kathleen Shields, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Seymour and Zoya Slive, 1954-1978 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Russell and Annette Smith, 1976, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Southwest Jewish Community Center, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Berniece Stewart, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Susie Stone (Hammersley's Sister), 1949-2003, (7 folders) (Box 4, Folder 37-43)
  - T Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Tamarind Institute, 1973-2001 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Victoria and Dave Thorne, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Tobey C. Moss, 1981-2003 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Tom and Diana Torres, 1981-1998 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Mort and Maxine Traylor, circa 1960-1996, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 49-50)
  - U Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - University of California, Santa Barbara, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - University of New Mexico, 1968-1999 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - V Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Philip Van Aver, 1964-2004 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - W Miscellaneous, circa 1950-2001 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Tammy Webster, circa 1968-2000 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Mary Werbelow, 1969-1987 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Lawrence Weschler, circa 1999-2003 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Clary Westburg, 1981-1994 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Dwight Westburg, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Eric Westburg (Hammersley's Uncle), circa 1966-1973 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Westside Jewish Community Center, 1962-1973 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Western State Arts Foundation, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 64)